# Sanjida Afreen

sanjidaaf@outlook.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sanjidaa/ | https://sanjidaa.carrd.co/ | Toronto, ON

#### PROFILE OVERVIEW

Highly skilled Data Analyst with over 2 years of experience in developing advanced Power BI dashboards, application configuration, and data integration. Proven ability to troubleshoot application and integration issues, manage master data for new business needs.

#### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

Honors Bachelor of Science, Computer Science | York University

Toronto, ON | Apr 2024

Achievements: Dean's Honour Roll 2023-2024

Relevant Courses: Database Management System, Big Data Systems, Computer Network Protocols and Applications

**Additional Certifications: Google** Cybersecurity Professional, **Google** Data Analytics, **Microsoft** Cybersecurity Analyst Professional, Developing Serverless Solutions on **AWS**, NoSQL and DBaaS 101, **DevOps** on AWS, Scrum Master

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Data Analyst - Program Assistant | York University

Toronto, ON | Mar 2024 - Present

- Designed and implemented 5 advanced **Power BI** dashboards, enhancing feedback analysis efficiency by 40%, tracking student employment trends over 5 years to highlight a 700% program growth, and boosting job posting visibility by 25%.
- Conducted **Microsoft Forms** to collect detailed insights on student and employer satisfaction, utilizing **Microsoft Excel Power Query** for data transformation and **DAX** for sophisticated data modeling and analysis.
- Created and maintained **SharePoint sites** and lists as data sources for Power BI dashboards, enabling nightly refresh and automation to ensure up-to-date and accurate reporting.

### **Data Analyst Intern** | TC Energy

Calgary, AB | May 2022 – Apr 2023

- Built 6 **Power BI** dashboards handling over **3M** rows per dataset in collaboration with the Product Delivery team and integrated data from **Amazon Redshift** for enhanced performance.
- Mastered DAX, SQL, and Power Query to boost data analysis and visualization efficiency.
- Resolved over 80 IT service requests via **ServiceNow**, improving response times and user satisfaction, with proficiency in QA testing and validation environments.
- Developed Canvas and Model-Driven **Power Apps** for streamlining licensing processes for **Liquid Pipelines** business, improving their efficiency by 40% through **PowerAutomate** workflow solutions.
- Ensured high data security in Power Platform development, aligning with industry compliance standards.
- Integrated multiple data sources, including **Dataverse** and **SharePoint** to deliver enhanced and comprehensive data-driven user experiences.

### **Cloud Developer Intern** | *TC Energy*

Calgary, AB | Jan 2022 - May 2022

- Developed web applications using **AWS Amplify, React, Lambda (Python)**, and **API Gateway**, following **Agile** methodologies and **Azure DevOps** for secure project management and documentation.
- Improved code quality and reduced post-production issues by 20% through **Pytest** framework.

# **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

## Job Posting Analysis Dashboard <a href="https://github.com/Sanjida-a/JobPostingAnalysis">https://github.com/Sanjida-a/JobPostingAnalysis</a>

June 2024

- Transformed and analyzed raw job postings data using **Python** and **Power Query Editor**, ensuring consistency.
- Built automated ETL pipelines, storing data in **SharePoint** and importing it as a web data source for further processing.
- Utilized ChatGPT-40 to analyze and categorize job skills and responsibilities, creating meaningful groupings.
- Developed interactive **Power BI** dashboards for stakeholders, featuring real-time data insights and key performance metrics.
- Implemented **DAX** queries to calculate metrics such as the count of positions and seasonal/academic year categorizations.

# $\textbf{Sales Management Dashboard} \ \underline{\textit{https://github.com/Sanjida-a/SalesAnalysis}}$

May 2024

- Developed an executive sales report for sales managers using Power BI, featuring daily updates and filters for real-time insights.
- Extracted and transformed data using SQL, SQL Server Management Studio, and Microsoft Excel.
- Designed a comprehensive data model in Power BI using DAX, connecting sales and budget data for detailed analysis.
- Visualized business proposal, user stories and profiles using Canva for clarity and stakeholder alignment.

### **LEADERSHIP & ACTIVITIES**

### **Co-op Program Assistant**

York University

Mar 2024 - Present

Toronto, ON

- Organized a welcome event for 75+ students with 98% turnout; managed budgeting and planning.
- Created an FAQ section on the program website by analyzing question patterns from hosting drop-in sessions, enhancing student resources and support.
- Managed and moderated a Discord channel, facilitating student engagement and providing real-time assistance.

### **Community Co-Chair of Student Committee**

TC Energy

• Led four major events with over 92 attendees each, enhancing student internship experiences with over 90% turnout.

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

Calgary, AB

• Managed weekly planning sessions, handled \$1,500 in budget proposals, and coordinated event logistics across sub-committees.

## **SKILLS**

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C, Python, SQL, DAX
- Developer Tools: Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, Git, MySQL, JUnit, Node, Power Query
- Security Frameworks and Compliance: NIST, INFOSEC, Regulatory Compliance
- Project Management: Leading smaller projects or initiatives, RPA and Power BI development.
- Technical Writing: Proficient in technical writing and documentation, experience with Visio.